There we go.
And I'm going to go ahead and admit
everybody from the room.
There we go.
And so good afternoon, everybody.
This is Dominic Serlo with the New Mexico
Department of Health and the medical
cannabis and psilocybin.
And we just are waiting for a few people
to still join.
But in the meantime,
this is the combined committee meeting
for Training and education and the end of
life care committees.
And so while we wait for a few other
people to join on in, at this point,
I will see.
Brenda,
did you have anything that you would like
to say as Chair of the Training and
Education Committee?
Yeah, Well, first of all,
I want to welcome everyone to the meeting
today.
We can't do it without you.
All of your input is very,
very important to us in developing this
program.
So as we move on,
if anybody wants to make an introduction,
we'll go ahead and make space for that
right now.
So if anybody is interested in
introducing themselves,
please just go ahead and raise your hand
and we'll go ahead and we'll unmute your
mic before we actually do that.
Johnny,
just as a reminder to everybody as we are
recording the meeting.
And so since we are recording it,
Please remember to keep and make sure
that your language stays appropriate for
the recording so we can post it on our
website.
Thank you.
Go ahead.
John.
Sounds good.
And is that a reminder if you want to
raise your hand that there's a icon at
the top banner that just says raise next
to a hand icon.
And first up, we've got Don Moser.
And Don, I've enabled your mic,
you can unmute.
Good afternoon.
I'm Don Moser.
I live in Las Vegas, NM.
I'm not affiliated with anyone,
but I'm excited about the health
potential of this new program and I
appreciate it being a part of it.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks, Don.
Let's see.
And next we've got Kate Hawk.
Kate, I have enabled your mic.
Hello again, everybody.
I'm Kate Hawk in Santa Fe.
I'm a trauma therapist,
psychedelic therapist and trainer and
especially involved with end of life care.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks.
And next we've got Denali Wilson.
And Denali, I have enabled your mic.
Good afternoon again.
My name is Denali Wilson.
I am the director of strategic support
for the Healing Advocacy Fund,
which is a nonprofit that supports state
regulated access and focused on equity
and access and affordability.
Yeah,
happy to be a part of this committee.
Awesome.
Thanks, Denali.
Let's see.
And I see Larry.
Looks like Larry was able to join.
So if if you wanna say say any
introductions or anything, Larry.
Yeah.
Hi, everybody.
This is Larry Lehmann.
I'm from UNM,
researcher in psychedelic therapies,
addiction, family medicine.
I'm part of the Advisory Board and chair
of the end of launch committee and
delighted to be with everybody here.
I am having some Internet issues from
home.
So I'm I'm on my phone here.
And Johnny, I sent you my PowerPoint.
I think it might be better if you run the
PowerPoint rather than me due to these
Internet problems,
but will do OK All right, let's see.
And next we've got Chris Caldwell and
Chris, I've enabled your mic.
You can unmute when ready.
Hi all,
Chris Caldwell with end of life
psychedelic care and we provide free
online events education,
educational programs that it consists of
online events and then professional
courses related to anything end of life,
palliative care and end of life.
Awesome.
Thanks, Chris.
Let's see.
And it looks like that was all the hands.
I saw it for now.
And we do have a couple introductions in
the chat.
We've got Sky Rivers with the Santa Fe
reporter doing coverage on the
legalization for psilocybin and a retired
intuitive counselor.
And we've got Gregory Evans,
independent researcher and armchair
mycologist.
No former or sorry,
no formal affiliations.
And just as a reminder,
because there were a few people who
joined in after we did the initial
announcement,
if there's anyone who would like to
introduce themselves,
please go ahead and raise your hand and
we will unmute your mic so you can
introduce yourself.
Oh, there we go.
All right.
And next,
we've got Hanitha Nyo and I have enabled
your mic.
You can unmute.
Thank you.
Good afternoon everyone.
This is an Ethan now Washington here in
Santa Fe, NM.
I am the Co director of the Psychedelic
Mental Health Access Alliance,
also a certified suicide facilitator and
really happy to be here today.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks Anitha.
And the next we've got Jamie Beachey and
I have enabled your mic.
You can unmute.
Hi everyone,
I'm Jamie Beachey calling from Santa Fe
and I am a field scholar with the Emory
Center for Psychedelics and Spirituality,
also a professional chaplain and chaplain
educator.
I was, I noticed in the last meeting we,
we noted that not everyone can access the
chat and I and I'm it's disabled for me
this time as well.
And so I'm wondering if there's a way to
enable the chat for everyone just to save
some of the need to speak directly into
the space.
Yeah, thank you, Jamie.
Thank you, Jamie.
And we do understand that it's actually
not an issue with the teams or the
meeting itself.
It's unfortunately,
some ISPs and service providers or
organizations have limitations with being
able or with allowing people to write
things in the chat.
And so unfortunately,
there's not much we can do about that.
We have double checked multiple times
throughout over the last several months
and it's unfortunately not something
that's on our side that we can control.
So we try to do the best we can,
including either in the chat or allowing
for the microphone space.
And also, as always,
at the end of the meeting,
we post the information if someone wants
to send comments or suggestions through
the e-mail address.
And so we try to ensure that we can do
that as best we can,
but unfortunately there are just some
limitations.
It's also why we do some of the meetings
as hybrid to include personal attendance
as well.
OK, thank you for clarifying.
Yeah, I'm,
I'm just on a personal Microsoft account,
but I'll go into the settings and see if
I can figure it out for myself.
Thank you.
Yeah,
one one other thing too that has worked
for some people,
if they're able to open it in a browser,
sometimes,
like depending on the browser they use,
it will be visible.
So it it it'll just be a troubleshooting
thing, unfortunately, on, on the user end.
Let's see.
OK, so next.
Yeah, no problem.
And next we've got Deb Thorne.
And Deb, I've enabled your mic.
You can unmute.
Hey guys.
Hello.
I'm Deb Thorne.
I'm the founder of Soltrip and Medicina
del Sol Integrative Healthcare in Las
Cruces, NM.
I am a medical provider and I'm certified
in ketamine and psychedelic medicine and
integrative mental health.
It's wonderful to be here.
Awesome.
Thank you, Deb.
And next we've got Vincent Espinosa and
Vincent.
I have enabled your mic.
You can unmute.
Will do.
Hello everyone, Vincent Espinoza here.
I'm the owner and founder of Heartwired
Healing.
It's a trauma therapy and psychedelic
facilitation practice based in New Mexico.
Actually just finished my Fluence
training and am actively going through my
practicum through Prati in Denver and am
licensed as an LCSW in Colorado, Oregon,
New Mexico, among eight other states.
So just happy to be here and hold space
with everyone and talk about this
important program.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks, Vincent.
And I'm just gonna catch a couple of the
introductions in the chat.
We got Caroline Kroland Fireside project.
I'm happy to have you.
And let's see Jessica Eden,
LCSWLAC Certified Psychedelic assisted
therapist and natural medicine
facilitator in private practice.
No formal affiliations.
All right,
And next we've got Chris Peskuski.
And Chris, I've enabled your mic.
You can unmute.
Good afternoon, everyone.
Chris Peskuski, Advisory Board member,
veteran, and just happy to be here.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks, Chris.
And let's see.
Last,
looks like we've got Lisa Ginsburg and I
have enabled your mic and you can unmute.
Thank you.
My name is Lisa.
I'm the Program Director of Changa
Institute and happy to contribute as much
as I can.
Awesome.
Thanks, Lisa.
And next we've got Paul.
And let's see, I have enabled your mic.
You can unmute.
Hi, everyone.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Awesome.
Thank you.
My name is Paul Walton.
And founder and director of Firefighters
for Plant Medicine and also Burnley,
a county firefighter for over 18 years
with peer support and system training and
everything like that.
And just, yeah,
excited and happy to be here.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks, Paul.
And then in the chat, let's see,
we've got Soma Franks,
current student in MA counseling program
at Southwestern College in Santa Fe,
and Catherine Warnock,
licensed counselor in Las Cruces,
owner of Mariposa Counseling Center and
director of education with Pata Silicide
and Assisted Therapy Association.
OK, anyone else need an introduction?
OK, thank you.
And I, and I just want to remind people,
you know, conduct in these meetings is,
you know, we, this is,
this is recorded and does get published
outside of the, you know,
for the public to, to review.
So, yeah, watch the curse words.
And Brenda,
I just want to because we did have quite
a few people still join during the last
round.
I just want to make sure if there's
anyone who would like to introduce
themselves,
please go ahead and raise your hand and
we will unmute your mic.
And while we give people a moment to do
that,
we do have a couple additional
introductions in the chat,
so I'll just go ahead and read those.
Deb Thorne,
founder of Soltrip and medicine, del Sol,
Integrative Healthcare in Las Cruces, NM,
medical provider certified in ketamine
and psychedelic medicine and integrative
mental health, soltrip.org.
And then we have Eileen Brewer,
patient educator,
coordinator with Cluster Busters.
And then another hand up,
we've got Erica Gergich.
And I have enabled your mic and you can
unmute.
Hi.
Yeah, this is Erica Gergorich.
And I'm an associate professor at the
School of Social Work at New Mexico State
University.
And we're going to be going through U pep
training in Madison this summer and very
excited to hopefully have some
educational programming at New Mexico
State in the future.
Awesome, thank you.
And then a couple more in the chat,
Jen Romero,
first responder and crime victim advocate
in Joy Stearns, grief,
loss and trauma informed somatic grief
specialist based in Santa Fe,
a certified somatic psychedelic
facilitator and end of life efficient.
OK.
And we'll make one more call.
If there's anyone else who would like to
introduce themselves,
please raise your hand.
All right, and Doctor Lita Fatimi,
I have enabled your mic.
You can unmute.
Hi everybody.
I,
I typed in my name correctly for this
meeting.
I'm Doctor Lita Fatimi and I'm like
academic hospitals by training and and
end of life physician.
I work with ABQ Hospice and Palliative
and also geriatrics,
and I'm also the founder of the Conscious
Physician Psychedelics Academy.
So glad to be here.
Great.
I think we have everyone then at this
time, Brenda.
So did you have anything you wanted to
add, Brenda, or shall we go to Larry?
No, I think that's that is about it.
Yeah.
Larry, do you want to take it away?
And let's get started and I may ask
questions while you're presenting.
I, you know, I'll keep my mouth shut,
let you let you run the show here, Brenda,
always happy to hear from you.
So I look forward to this.
This is, this is actually kind of,
I think it's sort of an exciting meeting.
I believe this is the first time we've
had two committees come to meet together.
And I know that a lot of us have talked
about that.
We need to start doing that.
We need to be kind of understanding
what's happening between,
between the different committees.
So, and I'm excited about doing that.
My,
my role is sharing the end of life
committee and what,
what right to do here is to bring a
proposal, sort of a proposal,
but a PowerPoint that goes over what
we've been doing in our committee and
then actually address more of the issue
of, you know,
training and education and end of life.
So this is,
I'll try to keep this maybe about 20
minute presentation.
It'll kind of get everybody up to date on,
on end of life.
And it's fine with me if people, you know,
have questions, you know,
while I'm talking,
it's also fine if people want to wait
till the end.
Either way, it's good for me.
I don't have the ability to control the
slides,
so I'll need to have some help posting
them up there.
Johnny, do you have that?
You were able to load them up?
Yeah, just one moment.
I've gotta get it from the emails here.
Just one second.
We have trouble at U&
M sometimes in using Teams.
You know,
it's like one part of the New Mexico has
trouble talking to the other part of New
Mexico.
Yeah, we, we run into the same issue,
Larry, But you know what the good part is,
is that we do our best and we continue no
matter what the obstacles are.
Yeah,
this little phone works well when the
computer doesn't.
Yes.
So I'll start and, and Larry,
just before you start,
can other people see the the slide
presentation?
We just want to ensure that yes,
we're seeing several thumbs up and thank
you, everyone.
All right, go ahead, Larry.
It is all yours.
Larry, are you having, is your mic on?
I actually wait.
Where did Larry go?
I don't know if that is his name.
Come back, Larry.
Let's give him a let's give him a minute
and see if he could come back on.
And in the meantime,
I'll just sort of fill in a little bit
Larry, Doctor,
Larry Lehman and he is with U&M.
And So what he really wanted to present
on,
and we'll present in just a few moments
once we get him back,
is some of what the End of life Care
Committee has come up with,
as well as about what they are doing as
far as research at UNL.
Hopefully we'll have them back in just a
moment.
So please bear with us, everyone.
Yeah.
And I don't want to take over because I
don't.
He may have some things that he needs to
say.
So yeah, let's just be patient.
If anyone has a question, if you know,
we can probably answer any general
questions at this moment just to pass the
time if you need to.
Oh, and here comes Larry now.
OK, OK, am I?
Am I back?
You are back, Larry.
So perfect timing actually.
So the presentation is yours.
So please go on ahead.
OK, good.
And I may have loaded,
it's a little confusing to do this for my
phone.
So this may be not the twice final
presentation.
So I will address things that may be a
little different from the side.
So let's start at the beginning here.
And these scopes and responsibilities
here are ones that we've kind of looked
at throughout the time of we've had the
committee,
the ones that we* or ones that we think
are more relevant for this, this,
this meeting,
the therapeutic team development,
education,
workforce development and establishing
the scope for end of end of life care.
You know, as we start here,
like there's some recommendations that
came out of our,
our last couple of meetings,
and I wanted to share those up front.
One of those is that end of life
psychedelic assisted care differs from
the other indications of being a stage of
life and not a disease diagnosis.
And so there may be we,
we see there's ways that we may have
variations in how we're,
we bring our part of the program forward.
We do recommend that each member of the
end of life care team have at least 15 to
20 hours of training specific to this
area,
which could occur during overall
psychedelic assisted therapy training
versus separate training.
We've discussed the spiritual care
component should be offered and supported
when desired and requested,
which might be a psychedelic chaplain or
traditional indigenous healer or through
other members of the care team.
Next slide.
So one question that comes up is what is
the definition of, you know,
definition of, of end of life?
And as we,
we actually had another slide that
actually gave more, you know,
more of the variation here.
But kind of the summary of this is that
this is not meant to be for end of life.
We're not meeting restricting to Hospice
care either either palliative care and
that it's maybe relevant when people have
had a diagnosis,
maybe relevant to someone who, you know,
has a life expectancy of, you know,
the number of years, but has, you know,
developed cancer, other other ones.
So we're feeling that it's going to be
having an expensive definition rather
than limited to actually Hospice the last
six months of life care.
And again,
this is a little more the slide that I
did mention,
we do actually have the slide.
So this is the one that mentioned you may
have a terminal illness,
you may have a serious or life limiting
conditions approaching a minute
transmissions.
And so it's not a single moment.
And so it's an expansive definition of
end of life.
Next slide,
the therapeutic team development,
we take the take the view that this
extends beyond strictly medical providers
and licensed therapist model and that we
want to be including palliative care,
hospital based nurses, social workers,
related professionals explore emerging
roles such as psychedelic end of life
digitalism, psychedelic chaplains.
I should mention that our committee,
we've done a series of educational
sessions where we've had presentations
from psychedelic chaplains,
presentation from see Chris Caldwell
focus on from end of life care and from
psychedelic dealers.
That and let's actually skip that last
point though.
Let's go to the next slide.
OK.
So the site of end of life care, you know,
I,
I think it's still to be determined how
that's going to play out in the whole
program.
We still have to work on what are the
legalities and regulations.
But you know,
our committee has felt strongly that end
of life care needs to be able to occur,
you know,
in in the home shouldn't be restricted to,
you know,
license facilities that we want to
develop models of care that, you know,
can be applied beyond the home that they
could be provided at different different
centers,
but that are accessible for people who
who are at home.
And we also want to be coordinated with
Hospice organizations,
home health centers and health and
therapy facilities.
Next slide.
So the model as we're describing here is
again designed for in home care.
I think the reason I think we all know
this, but just to remind us,
you know why we're saying that people
prefer to be in familiar surroundings.
People may have limited mobility.
They desire the presence of the of their
home network and that the home in home
delivery model is, you know,
can complement, but it's actually,
you know,
separate from Hospice care as as people
may know,
Hospice care is limited to the last six
months of life.
I would say we've had a beautiful
presentation actually at the last meeting
from Red Willow and we actually appear to
have one of the one of the 1st and most
developed psychedelic hospices in the
country.
Can go to the next slide.
Do you guys still hear me?
Here we go OK it's fun doing this off
your iPhone.
So talk when we talk about education,
workforce development, you know again,
we want to emphasize the idea that that
we feel like everyone who's going to work
in the end of life area needs some
specific training.
Now how they get that training we could
be very variable.
People may have received that during
their you know training and a facilitator
or a psychotherapy, you know training.
But we've noted that many programs don't
have 20 hours.
If not,
then our recommendation is that we have
some training here that's available
either in state or out of state.
One thing we want to do is try to clarify
the role of the lead lead practitioner
and we're today going to propose a role
for assistance to the lead practitioner
as one way of expanding the involvement
of people and expanding the different
roles.
Next slide.
So the the lead practitioner can can be
held as as people may know from other
committee meetings by various people.
It can be mental health professionals,
medical professionals,
chaplains or spiritual care providers.
We have to row here trained facilitators
from non clinical or community based
pathways that appears that that may not
be does not appear to be an option in New
Mexico to have the role of lead
practitioner.
But we have in our committee, you know,
discussed various ways that we can expend
the expended so that people can be
involved in offering this care even if
they don't have a a licensed next slide.
SO11 idea of practicers from clinical non
clinical or community based pathways
would be a some of that might be known as
the death doula that death doula doesn't
have an access.
And again,
this slide is a little bit out because I
changed this one doesn't actually have a
route in our state to for a direct entry
as they will lead practitioner as a
facilitator.
But we're going to describe other roles
where the person is the death doula or an
indigenous healer,
different ways that they can be involved
as part of the care team.
Next slide.
OK, so this was some came out of,
you know, our last median conversations,
the idea of and we we like the name.
We hope people appreciate that,
that this is a space attendant.
And the idea of the space attendant is,
you know,
there's numerous entendres for that word,
but it's an abbreviation of supporting
psychedelic assisted care at the end of
life attendant role.
And it's also as a holder space,
which is a term that we often talk about
in psychedelic therapy.
The idea as a person in that role would
be providing continuous grounded presence
and relational support through the care
process and supporting the license lead
practitioner, the client and other people.
It can be a potential as a pathway for
practicum experience,
a pathway for ongoing mentorship.
Part of the reason for creating this role,
there's multiple reasons.
One is we do strongly recommend that when
this care occurs in the home that there
need to be two members of the care team
at home.
We do appreciate that there may be
limitations on on that happening,
whether it's financial or actually people
there.
This would allow the lead practitioner to
along with the the space attendant.
We have more flexibility.
When we talk about end of life care,
we we feel fairly,
we're confident that there's actually a a
good pool of people who want to help with
this,
volunteers that could be people that are
in training, people retired,
different people that would like to help
with this role.
We will talk about the training for this
role that's relevant to this committee.
We've made some recommendations on how to
train a space attendant next slide.
So here's the qualifications,
completion of a space attendant training
and you're probably going what is a space
attendant training.
So what we've talked about here is that
we envision that requiring probably about
a 40 hour training.
Twenty of those would be the similar to
what we mentioned about end of life
psychedelic care,
but we also wanted to adapt to training
that would be similar to what's used by
Zendo.
Zendo is psychedelic, you know,
emergency care that often happens at
festivals, public, public events requires,
you know, about,
I think it's about 30 hours of training.
So that could be blended in here.
So while the person is getting trained in
end of life psychedelic, you know,
care to be supportive,
they also are just getting experience
working with people that are having
challenging experiences.
Compensation,
we're thinking this role could be a
stipend or a volunteer role would be one
way of it being covered.
Next slide,
so additional care team members mentioned
here being actually before I before I go
to that,
I want to actually go to another slide
that is that was left out here that we
think that there are a lot of other
people that have a role that they could
be that they could be involved in.
What that role is called is still a clear,
it could be potentially called a,
a facilitator role.
This could be a role that, for instance,
a it could be fulfilled by a I am a a
death doula that received additional
training.
It could be received that role for
somebody who's a legacy provider and has
the experience.
It could be somebody who's a indigenous
provider Corindero different roles that
this would be ways spiritual care
providers for this who are not lead
practitioners could could feel in that
role as well.
So that would be different role than the
space team.
The space team person we're talking about
is more just directly,
directly assisting the person who's the
facilitator could be working with the
lead practitioner.
And even though we're calling them the
facilitator, lead practitioner,
I think we've had some recognition that
that actually can be flipped a little bit.
It may be appropriate, you know,
for a situation where the lead
practitioner sort of steps to the
background and the facilitator may hold,
you know, ceremony for people there.
So they would have the the licensed
practitioner there,
but they may take a role or,
or we may have people that are, you know,
otherwise legacy Indigenous death duos
who really are fully capable of the
competency of taking a strong role there.
Even though they're not the, quote,
licensed provider,
they could be a lead provider.
The the other thing is just additional
care members that we described as as
client, client directed.
That could be family members and
spiritual care providers or Chaplins that
are not licensed providers, death duels,
as I mentioned,
a culture or community based providers
and even other people,
somatic integration practitioners that
that.
So even if there's not a direct role and
training that the that the client could
bring in people that they want, of course,
during this is something that people have
control over.
Next slide.
So as we were kind of been, you know,
coming up their list and sort of what you
see as see as our suggestions here,
we also came up with areas that we're,
we're feeling as a committee,
we need to have direction.
One of them is, and I,
I should mention that Dom and I had a
wonderful phone call yesterday where he
helped share a lot with me.
And so I,
I already know the answer to some of
these, but medicine handling,
who can transport and administer medicine,
like how is that going to,
is that going to happen?
It may be particularly important if
that's happening in the home preparation,
integration,
Who's responsible for those phases in
home care?
What are safety thresholds and protocols?
Let me actually pause that that about the
safety threshold because there's one
slide again that got left out of the ones
that are on my phone here,
which is actually recognizing that end of
life care,
that there's maybe different needs for
safety and support depending on the
person's history.
One way of approaching that is to look at
people who are facing the end of life
care and also have a history of trauma.
They have history of PTSD,
they have significant life trauma in that
situation, you know,
recommending that may not be a situation
where it would be appropriate to just
have the licensed provider and the space
team attendant where that consideration
should be given to me having to pull
people who are fully trained and ideally
one one of them that has a history of
working with people, people in trauma.
I'll share just a little bit of my
experience in in doing psychedelic
research at UNM and that we've had a
study of major depressive disorder.
We screen people for hours for that.
We've had several people who describe no
history of actually trauma and they
actually experienced their first
realization of their childhood trauma
during that.
So we,
we want to maintain an awareness that
even though we look at people that have
more risk or less risk that everybody may
may have more,
more traumatic events that need to
process.
One thing that we talked about is
depending on who the,
the licensed practitioner is, you know,
to have resources available.
And this may be something that's easier
in Santa Fe or Albuquerque or Las Cruces.
But you know that the idea of somebody
else who could be involved,
they may have attended A preparation,
they may be a more of a fully trained
psychotherapist and would be available in
those situations where more deeper trauma
emerges.
And then a couple more questions just to
throw out here.
You know, the care team coordination,
who's coordinating and designating it,
how we're assembling the team,
our role clarity, team cohesion,
coordination.
You know, as I,
you've heard me describe a couple of
models.
One model is for having two, you know,
full end of life practitioners and others
to have one space attendant.
I think there's a lot of different models.
You know,
our thought that as we're is as we're
moving forward,
forward that we probably outline the
different ways the models and what kind
of support and resources would be
available outside of that reimbursement.
I think is is a big issue that we have to
look at,
especially as we're talking about
involving multiple people on the care
team.
And we do think that the space space
attendant is one way to do this in an
economical way when it's appropriate.
But we also recognize that there are
situations where people may need more
support from the second person than that.
And I think that's the last slide there.
Yep, great.
Well, thanks.
I think I hopefully I kept within close
to my close to my 20 minutes there.
I didn't I didn't see if anything bring a
hook on me.
So I must have been OK with that there.
I,
I know I presented a lot of information.
I'm trying to summarize really kind of
our current state of the thoughts of our
committee.
All of these are kind of an evolution.
We're very aware that there's not a,
a guideline yet for how to provide,
provide at home care,
but we were strongly want to, you know,
recommend that.
And, and as we get more information about,
you know, from this committee,
from the training and education committee
in the DoH,
we think we'll have a better idea how to
design the care team for, for our plans.
Well, I have a question, Larry.
So the way I'm looking at it through a
clinician's eyes,
I think it would be very important to
have this training with clinicians for
the psychedelic,
I mean for the psilocybin mental health
part of it.
So in other words,
this could be part of the training for
all clinicians who want to be part of
this because, you know,
at at this point in time,
nobody knows where they're going to be
called to.
And I think having that extra training
for end of life for clinicians to be
worked into the curriculum would be a
very important part to have in the
education and training.
Brenda, I agree with you 100%.
I think our team does as well.
But we're also recognizing that we may be
giving reciprocity to people who trained
in other sites that maybe they did a
training that didn't have that.
And so we want to have that as
consideration.
So hopefully if we have a once we have
our local trainings that would be
required.
But we do anticipate that there are
people that may be eligible to become
assume different roles and haven't had
that training.
We're on board with the idea that it
should be an integral part of training.
Oh yeah,
most definitely because it's it's
inevitable.
And I think that clinicians would become
more comfortable with end of life too,
because it's one of those things that I
myself as a clinician have only since
I've been practicing, I've only had one,
one client come in for therapy when their
life wasn't going to be, you know,
they weren't going to live much longer
than a year.
So that would bring in the scope of
practice for all clinicians.
And I think that's a very vital part of
learning that we miss in our practicum,
we miss in getting our master's degree.
Yes, we take, you know, a class in brief,
but we don't have a specific class in
actually end of life.
So I think that's something that has been
overlooked for a very long time and needs
to be in a curriculum.
Agree.
One idea would be,
let's say yourself or somebody else who
wanted to get that experience.
You could be in that role of assistant,
the space attendant position and actually
with the lead provider that has more
experience.
We were hesitant to require require that,
but I think it is worthy of the
discussion.
In other words,
we're saying 20 hours of end of life care.
In reality,
I think none of us really think that one
should go to being the licensed
practitioner for end of life care without
having had some experience.
And so whether that just becomes a
standard and regulation,
but I think that that's that's an
important question.
It's actually important question I think
for all of the scopes.
In other words, you know.
You know,
if you're going to be involved as the
lead practitioner,
what is your experience working with PTSD?
The, the, the different areas?
But,
but since we're focused on end of life,
we definitely did want to recommend
specific training.
And I think recommending some practical
training makes a lot of sense too.
Well, thank you, Larry, thank you.
OK,
I guess we're going to move on to who is
next with their hand raised.
Yeah, let's see.
Looks like we've got Lisa Ginsburg.
And Lisa, your mic is enabled.
You can unmute and ready.
Thank you.
And it's important conversation.
And just wanted to let you know that in
Oregon and Colorado,
end of life is included, not in dev,
but we're definitely covering several
classes on working with terminal ill
patients.
And like in our program,
we have amazing Chris Caldwell teaching
and she's an expert in end of life here.
And I think considering including that in
the general training for practitioners is
definitely a must.
Thank you, Lisa.
All right.
And Chris Caldwell, your mic is enabled.
You can unmute.
Well, thank you, Lisa.
This makes for a great Segway.
Yeah,
I have a lot of thoughts that we probably
won't get to today necessarily because
there's a lot of options it sounds like
here.
But of course, what,
what end of life psychedelic Care does
offer is a series of trainings which can
be tailor made.
And I think what I'm hearing is let's
let's take Red Willow Hospice,
for example,
and I just spent the week with with them,
you know, psychedelic training.
They need clearly end of life care,
clearly not.
But there still may be a couple of
courses that would be useful to them in
terms of applying psilocybin to end of
life care.
So there still may be a couple of of
courses or number of hours that that
should be taken.
And to Lisa's point, yeah,
folding in a discussion about end of life
care to this general training makes a
whole lot of sense to me.
However, I will say, having done this and,
and we offer,
we offer a lot of different courses,
working with people toward the end of
life can be very different.
And there's a whole lot of skills that I
think need to be taught.
And the other thing I'd like to mention
is that when we talk about end of life
care,
I really love how Larry and the team have
expanded that definition.
So if you're working with somebody with a
serious illness,
that's nothing like necessarily working
with somebody who's really close to the
end of life,
maybe has life sustaining equipment in
their home, requires a, you know,
physician's orders for sustaining life
treatment.
So,
so we're running the gamut of taking care
of people,
especially if we're talking about taking
care of the people in the home,
that's going to require some specialized
training.
So I just wanted to make that point.
And then I guess Brenda for you,
since since my organization specializes
in end of life training and I don't
foresee going through an approval process
to offer a, you know,
a generalized psychedelic training,
will you accept applications for sort of
adjunct training along these lines?
I think at this point in time, we're,
we're looking at everything.
Nothing's nothing's off the table.
And I think that, you know,
this would be be considered, you know,
I mean,
there's because we're all coming in all
at the same time and we're trying to
navigate this.
But I think, yeah,
I think there's space for for this.
And I think this is just taking a look at
what the competencies need to be written
out and and see what the Department of
Health will except in the the curriculum
that we're going to provide.
But, yeah,
I think right now things are still wide
open and and open for discussion.
Yeah.
Thank you, Brenda.
Sure.
All right.
And next we've got Catherine Warnock.
And Catherine, I've enabled your mic.
You can unmute.
Hello, I first of all,
I just was wondering are we just focusing
on end of life for this two hours or
because I have some things I want to
discuss or bring up One of them was Larry
actually brought up?
I just wasn't sure if now is the time or
should I wait until later because I want
to talk more generalized and I don't want
to.
I want to make sure that this is
effective.
So should I wait till later or is now an
OK time?
Brenda, I'll answer that if if it's OK.
OK.
Yeah, because I got a little what?
OK.
So Catherine, and,
and also for other people is I do have a
little bit of some basic requirements.
And this is just an outline that I'm
going to present here in a few minutes.
We just wanted to get some of the
feedback with regard to what Larry
presented first.
And it does kind of go over that.
And so that might actually be more
appropriate for what you're thinking.
Catherine,
but but if you want to talk about it now,
that's OK too.
No, I'm fine.
I'm fine with waiting.
I'd like to keep us on task.
Thank you.
All right.
Sounds good.
Let's see.
So next we've got Hanifa and you can
unmute when ready.
Hi.
Good afternoon.
Just wanted to reiterate and lift up
standardized whatever training that
Mexico comes up with respective of
reprocity in in other states that there
should be a baked in module on end of
life psychologist secure and then that
module itself can I would recommend it
also standing alone.
So if someone had doesn't have that
competency,
they can just supplement their their
certification or certificate of licensing
with that specific module.
I think that's just a a way to take into
consideration other modules that might
won't be pulled out that can be that can
cover those competencies that people
don't have it.
So I hope that makes sense.
That's excellent.
Yes, I think going forward there,
there are going to be gaps in people's
education.
So I think actually highlighting a lot of
these as part of the core competencies
would be like, let's say you know,
it's an additional hour or two,
you can tack,
tack that on as far as training goes,
because everyone is going to have some
gaps.
And we want to be as comprehensive in the
education as much as possible because
this is going to be a lot to incorporate.
I know there's going to be things that we
will miss and maybe some things that we
there may be overkill on.
So going forward,
I think going over all of this with a
fine tooth comb and finding you know what,
what you,
what you lack as an individual therapist
or a practitioner in some scope is,
is very important because we don't want
to miss that important part because there
will be they'll,
they'll probably be a test and there'll
probably be some readings and all kinds
of things as far as training goes.
So we don't want to miss anything.
And I think the other departments are
doing a wonderful job at finding all of
the nooks and crannies of what we need to
pay attention to here in New Mexico
because other states have missed and they
rushed in too quickly.
And so I think this is a really great
platform to kind of get it out there and
and state that.
So Erica,
thank you very much for mentioning these
little like notes that we need to study.
Wonderful.
Thank you.
All right.
And next we've got Erica and I have
allowed your mic.
You can unmute one.
Ready.
Right.
And just as a reminder, there's a oh,
yeah, there you go.
Sorry.
It wouldn't wouldn't let me click it.
I had to control shift mic.
I've got a couple of questions.
First,
I was wondering about any requirements
for continuing education because it's,
you know,
quickly and always evolving field just to
make sure that you know,
we're we have evidence based best
practices.
That's the first question.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Because this is this is a field that that
is continuingly being studied.
Like this morning I heard of a study on I
think it was psilocybin in fish and it
was on aggression in fish.
And I think that the aggression came down
in fish.
So as, as, as time goes on,
we're going to be adding more new things.
And I think the more we have in in the
teaching, the better,
but it's going to be a lot to try to keep
on top of all of the the latest greatest
modalities or studies or research.
So this I definitely will see this
continuing going on.
So it, it would probably be worked into,
you know, your CE us,
if you are a practicing clinician or a
nurse practitioner or anything like that.
It's,
it's whether it will be a requirement or
not, I don't know.
But I suspect that that, you know,
keeping up to date with all the latest
greatest information is what we're trying
to do here and learn.
So thank you.
My second question is thank you for that.
My second question is,
are there any thoughts on institutions
becoming certified providers for offering
education, evidence based education?
Because like our School of Social work at
New Mexico State is a provider for
continuing education for social workers
in New Mexico, for example.
We're just an institution that has been
given an allowance to do that.
Has that come up at all or any thoughts
on that?
So good.
Good afternoon, Erica.
And yes,
it's any of those institutions would be
able to apply to be able to be
educational providers through the program,
but those rules are not yet written.
So those the programs would have to meet
the requirements and as long as they do
then they would be open to apply.
OK, great.
Thank you so much.
I'd like to address some of the comments
or just say the comments here in the chat
here.
I'm just rolling back here.
Well,
we haven't really been keeping up with
them.
Don't know where to start here.
Yeah, I think,
I think they started probably with Eileen
or at the 143 comment.
OK, Thank you.
And and Brenda,
what I would say is some of these
questions I think might actually be
answered by the portion that we're going
to be bringing in that we'll be
presenting here in just a few minutes.
So I would say to hold off just for a
little bit.
The one that I would say is,
is not really a part of what we're going
to present is Eileen's question.
As far as cost,
and I know we've addressed this before,
but the department cannot regulate cost
for training.
However, our hope is,
is that we are able to fine tune the
training so that the cost will not be
anywhere near what they have been in
other locations,
but we can't guarantee that at this time.
The other aspect of it is as far as that
goes,
is that we have also stated very clearly
that it is potentially possible that
there could be other resources that are
available to help providers to be able to
go through that training.
And we hope that that will become
something more widespread as those rules
come into effect.
And then as far as continuing education,
I think we've already answered that,
that yes, there will be,
But what exactly that consists of,
we don't know yet.
Thank you, Dominic.
And then I think Chris Caldwell still has
their hand up.
Well, yeah, Chris, you should be able to.
There you go.
I can thank.
Thank you.
I just.
Yeah.
I wanted to offer a couple more thoughts
going back to what Hanifa had said too,
about making sure that any,
and I'll just call it adjunct training.
In this case,
we're talking about end of life is part
and parcel,
whatever you think the generalized
training needs to incorporate.
However, I also agree with Larry,
end of life as training should require
somewhere between 15 and 20 hours.
So I don't think you want to tack that on
to the training you're going to require
everybody to take.
And I really love the idea of looking at
it from a continuing Ed perspective.
All of our courses currently offer CES
for social workers and nurses in the
state of New Mexico.
So I think that's a really great way of
handling it.
This says, yes,
here's your generalized training.
And then if you want further training at
any point in time, then you know,
you can sign up for end of life care
training.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Thank you very much for that.
Any other comments or questions from
anyone?
OK, if it's if there aren't, Brenda,
may I go ahead and present?
Sure.
Thank you.
OK, so good afternoon, everybody.
So I'm going to put this in the chat
rather than share it on the screen just
because it's a a Word document and I just
want to get it cleared.
And there's a couple of parts I'm going
to share.
So I'm going to go through these these
different portions first and then I'll
open it up for questions.
So please hold for just a minute so I may
answer them in another portion.
OK.
So the first portion of this is what
we're really looking at is what the basic
requirements.
So we're not talking about competencies
yet.
We're looking at just what the basic
requirements for individuals applying for
a permit to be in one of these roles as a
clinician, practitioner, facilitator,
etcetera.
And So what we're really looking at and
as a reminder,
the statute states that the clinicians
have to be licensed and approved New
Mexico healthcare providers.
And so that really fits in within the
first two categories.
So the diagnostic clinician and the
practitioner cause all of those are the
healthcare provider levels.
So the diagnostic clinician,
what they really are doing is they are
certifying the patient that they are
eligible for the medical psilocybin
program.
So essentially they are just simply
diagnosing that the individual has one of
the qualifying conditions.
They have a current valid license from a
recognized New Mexico licensing board
that allows diagnosing the qualified
medical condition within their scope of
practice.
They have a New Mexico controlled
substance number.
They've complete the required New Mexico
Department of Health training and as many
of you have asked about continuing
educational training requirements
annually and then that they apply,
receive and maintain the valid permit
from the Department of Health medical
psilocybin program in that diagnostic
clinician role.
The next step is the practitioner now and
this is that therapist behavioural health
level.
And so the person who essentially will be,
you know,
essentially will be there during the day
of administration.
They'll be the individual who is doing
the therapy both pre and post and
essentially will be that licensed
individual during those times.
So they have to have a current valid
license from a recognized New Mexico
licensing board that allows for the
delivery of counseling,
mental health therapy or behavioral
health therapy within their scope of
practice completed.
The New Mexico Department of Health
required training and continuing
education annually and then apply and
receive a maintain a valid permit from
New Mexico Department of Health Medical
Psilocybin program.
And then this third category is the
facilitator.
Now this is where as many people have
mentioned,
what do we do with regard to individuals
who do not have licensure?
How do we ensure under the statute that
they can be involved in this and this is
really that place where individuals can
be involved and so for this it's complete
the required Department of Health
training and continuing Ed requirements
and apply,
receive and maintain a valid permit from
Department of Health.
Now this facilitator portion, for example,
can be the the individual,
if they have a spiritual tradition,
if they are coming from that or a
different legacy tradition,
where they can be those individuals and
where they work in conjunction with the
licensed individual.
That way it still works under the statute
and yet allows for those other options to
be a part of this process and quite
frankly to be the lead portion in many
regards,
so long as that is negotiated with that
licensed individual on the therapy side.
Now someone for example,
such as a psychiatrist who holds both an
MD and the counseling side could be in
both of those first 2, the diagnosing,
the diagnosing clinician and the
practitioner level.
So you could have that sort of thing
where the same person actually applies
and receives that permit to be able to do
multiple levels.
And of course,
anybody who is in this would be able to
then go through the training as a
facilitator.
And again,
we're talking about facilitator in this
context as has been mentioned in many of
the other committees that often times are
called a trip sitter,
a guide facilitator and there are many
other terms utilized,
but that's really where this fits.
And the next part I want to talk about a
little bit is the alternative path
because that has had a lot of
conversation and I want to before I put
it up on to the into the chat,
I just want to mention that I have a time
frame in there,
but that is just a starting time frame
for the discussion.
So that is completely open.
We've just put it in as,
so we didn't just have XS,
quite frankly in there.
And so pardon me everyone,
I have to just copy it over.
And so the alternative path.
And again,
you should all be able to see that here
in just a few moments within there.
And and Doctor Sutter,
we will get to questions once I'm
finished.
So we'll get to that here at the end.
Give me just a few more minutes and I'll
be able to put this out.
And I have a few questions for the entire
group as well.
So the alternative path essentially is
that for the first year of the
implementation of the program that the
applicants can substitute for the
required DoH training and continuing Ed
requirements to have the proof that
they've completed an educational program
that's approved and in good standing by
the appropriate state of Oregon or state
of Colorado authorities.
So they're natural medicine in Colorado
and I forget the exact name in Oregon,
but they're appropriate authorities that
have approved for those programs.
And then of course,
they would still need to complete a
module specified by Department of Health
with regard to the the New Mexico
Psilocybin Act, the medical program rules,
regulations, cultural considerations,
because that's come through in several
committees.
So I want to make sure that's there.
And then whatever New Mexico Department
of Health issued guidance and best
practices and a lot of that is coming out
through some of the other committees
including for example,
the the patient requirements as well as
dosage and administration committees.
And so really looking at all of that.
So this would allow that alternative path.
And again, just as a note,
the first year was there as a placeholder
for during that first year of
implementation, but we can adjust that.
The main reason they'll use first year
when we when we put this in is simply
because it is something that has come up
in a couple of the meetings that for the
first year or so.
So we're starting with that first year.
So my first questions, well,
and before I get to that Doctor Sutter,
I'll answer your question about the
providers.
Again, providers are,
are something how many providers there
would need to be is actually something
that needs to be determined within that
administration aspect of it.
But our envisionment is that yes,
there actually would be the practitioner.
So that therapy level,
you would have at least one individual
who has that level of permit who would be
present during the administration and the
journey.
And then you also have the facilitators
who are there to provide a little more
one-on-one or one on two,
depending on what ratios get determined
with the patients directly.
That way.
For example, if you had say,
we did a one on two ratio and again,
those have not been determined yet,
But if we had that and we had four people
in a small group,
you would actually end up at that point
having 3 individuals who have permits who
are at these levels that are in the room
at a minimum.
But there would need to be a minimum from
a safety standpoint.
Dr.
Lehman brought it up very well.
We always look at it from a safety.
So there's always going to need to be at
least two individuals who have permits
during any point or time on a journey.
And that's just a safety aspect of that.
And I hope that helps.
So my questions to consider and again the
questions to consider is one year
reasonable for the reciprocity?
Should it be a different length of time?
And should that reciprocity be for all
level of permits or only some of them?
And then the other.
And I'll put these questions in the chat
by the way to everyone.
And then should there be any additional
different requirements or an endorsement
type requirement and under this would
fall what Doctor Lehman has suggested for
example, is this space attendant,
which great name by the way,
great acronym for those who don't recall
it's supporting psychedelic assisted care
and end of life or space attendees.
And so for that,
should there be that sort of a different,
I think I,
I can't remember who said anything,
it was Chris who may have said as an
adjunct,
should there be that sort of additional
endorsement or certification that's
required for end of life and potentially
for other conditions?
So I'm going to put those in the chat.
And then while I am doing that to answer
the question, Deb, no,
we do not yet know what those total hours
and what those will be.
We have talked about in the meeting after
this for training and education,
we're going to go through the list of
potential competency areas and that will
help us to determine what that length of
time, so approximately how many hours,
what exactly that'll consist of.
And again, on cost,
Department of Health does not have any
regulation or regulatory authority over
cost,
but our hope is that we can streamline it
enough to make it much more affordable
than what's happening currently in some
of the other states because we recognize
that's an issue anyway.
So with that,
I believe we have Hanifa has had their
hand up first.
So if we can have Hanifa unmuted,
can you hear me?
You should be good.
Yeah.
Hello.
Thank you, Dominic.
Thank you for that overview.
It's really helpful.
I have kind of two comment and a question.
The question is in the model that you
presented, Dominic,
who exactly on the administration day is
administering the medicine?
And then my other comment is on, again,
I'm just this is,
I'm going to be waving this flag very
often,
but thinking about the ongoing continuum
of care.
I'm helping to develop this thing called
the circle of care,
which is for a community based resource
to have the place of people to land after
they finish their clinical protocols.
And I'm curious about creating some type
of like not a permit, but like a, like a,
the state issues some sort of agreement
that they like people who are providing
ongoing care outside of the medical model
have a certificate of understanding of
what they're providing,
kind of like a vetting process.
So that when clients are coming out of
their clinical care or they can go to a
circular care website and say, oh,
here are clinicians in,
in New Mexico who have received this sort
of like vetting or,
or approval or have assigned kind of an
agreement or understanding of what it
means to provide ongoing care under the
state model.
So, so those are my, my,
my question and invitation, right.
So as far as the first one,
as far As for the administration,
in most cases it would really be a self
administration.
And once the medication which would need
to be delivered to the approved location,
because again,
remember all of this must occur in
approved locations,
but we haven't gotten yet to what exactly
those requirements are.
So, for example,
some of the things that Doctor Lehman
brought up earlier with regard to the
things happening at home,
we're trying to work through the
particulars,
the potential barriers and issues to
ensure that we could be able to do that
and and create those sort of approved
locations that are not just necessarily
in Wellness or you know, center,
but still in a therapeutic space.
But aside from that,
what would really happen is that the
medication would be delivered to the
center to the approved location.
And then the individual in most cases is
going to be self administering.
But in cases where they would not be able
to,
then that would be able to be done by the
facilitator where the facilitator would
be able to assist at that in that level.
So I hope that helps to answer that.
And then the second,
the second question you had as far As for
the therapists afterwards,
that should be done again as part of the
care team.
And it's one of the things we've talked
about in your circle of care really fits
in very well with regard to that.
And so with regard to the, the,
the circle of care,
really it should be that care team is
doing that to ensure that continuity of
care.
So to ensure that individuals who are who
are providing this therapy and especially
the integrative therapy afterwards have
gone through training.
And so the department will be putting
that up on the website as far as who is
permitted.
And so that patients will have a good
idea of who has been permitted,
who's gone through the training,
who has that understanding and be able to
select and hopefully they're selecting
them with the other care providers that
they're working with.
And so that really needs to needs to
occur at that.
You know,
that needs to occur in that public space
as far as who has been permitted.
But the patients will select that on
their own and again,
hopefully in conjunction with their other
care providers.
As to for Soma Franks, that has changed.
Soma just has in the chat about who the
approved Colorado or Oregon trainings are.
There are many trainings out there and
what I recommend is go to that state
website because they do change and that's
why I would say in there that they will
need to be programs that are approved and
in good standing.
And so you would just need to go to their
websites.
So anyway I hope that answers that.
The next one we have,
Paul is has the next hand up.
Hey, Dominique.
Thanks and thanks for that layout.
I, I like how this is coming together.
It looks pretty good.
One question I do have is that I know
I've heard from Colorado and Oregon
facilitators how expensive the state
facilitation license is.
So that's one thing that I kind of wanted
to see if you,
I'm sure you have thought about it.
I know that you.
So I just kind of see where you're
heading in that direction.
Thank you, Paul.
And it's almost like I planted that
question.
I appreciate it.
And just so everybody knows, I did not,
but it's a great question.
And we've said this in many other areas,
the permit side,
so this is not the training side because
the department again doesn't have
jurisdiction or the ability to regulate
cost of the training itself other than
how much training is required.
But the permits themselves are there's
not going to be a fee for those at least
in the initial phases of of the program
program.
And part of the reason for that is in
Oregon for example,
the program had to be self-sufficient and
so they had to get their operating money
through fees that they had to charge to
individuals for our program here the the
legislature did allocate funds for the
program.
And so we do not have to do that from an
operating expense.
And so at least in during the beginning
stages of the program,
there are not going to be fees.
And the reason I say beginning and I
can't actually,
actually guarantee that down the road is
I don't know what's necessarily going to
happen in 2-3 years myself.
If anybody has a crystal ball,
I would love to see it and please help me
with regard to that.
But at the beginning of the program at
initially and my hope is through the life
of it that there are not additional fees
so long as this is continued to be
supported through the legislative
allocations.
So thank you very much for that question,
Paul.
It gave me a chance to provide some
really great news.
I hope our next person in line is Lisa
Ginsburg.
All right, thank you.
I think it's an excellent idea to provide
reciprocity opportunity for programs to
provide training that are all the
licensed in Oregon and Colorado at least
for the first year.
My main concern is the rules in Mexico
and I think it will require an additional
module to cover the prescriber and basic
rules on the age and administration just
to protect future facilitators in the
state because if they don't know the
rules,
they potentially can endanger themselves.
So great, Lisa, that's a great,
great point.
And that's actually where that second
part of the alternative path comes in
with the module that's specified because
that would require,
that would be required still with regard
to even if someone has gone through
another program.
And that actually is specific to the
rules, the statute, the regulations,
what can and cannot be done here in New
Mexico because they are very different
from other places.
So that's a great point.
Thank you.
And and while I have you though,
since you brought up about the
alternative path,
do you think the year is a good time
frame or do you think it should be
greater, shorter?
You think it's a good time frame?
Thank you for the thumbs up.
I appreciate it.
OK.
Next we have is Chris Peskowski.
Hi Dominic.
Hi everyone.
I,
I do like the idea of having certain
endorsements for specific conditions,
you know,
especially representing the veteran,
veteran community with PTSDI know that
can be a little more complex sometimes
than maybe depression might be.
And so,
and especially the end of life situation.
I,
I think that is completely different and
having just recompleted facilitator
training,
I would be way out of my element in that
space.
So I think that's a great idea.
I have a question about,
you're talking about DoH training.
Is DoH going to be providing the training
specifically or is that going to be up to
the private market to provide DoH
approved training?
Great question, Chris.
And and again,
one that we've talked about in other
committees as well somewhat is that there
will be a module that will be a New
Mexico specific module that will be
created by Department of Health.
And that's the one that I'm talking about
that would be required for the
alternative path.
But also anybody who's going through the
training at all would have to do that.
But that part of the training,
that module would be offered free of
charge.
But the rest of it as that gets
determined as far as the other
competencies and areas,
that portion is going to be up to the to
the educational market.
And that's the part that I think
everybody's questioning and saying,
how much will it cost?
We really don't know that until we have
and know what those competencies are
gonna be.
How long is the training going to be?
Because again, educators,
most educators still have to be paid.
Although somebody in the earlier in the
chat said hopefully there'll be some
nonprofits and that would be part of my
hope as well.
I hope that answers it for you, Chris.
But before I also say that is so I did
get from you that you think that
potentially adding another additional
requirements or endorsement for
depression,
but definitely to have that for end of
life.
I think end of life and PTSD,
you know depression I think might be one
of the more simple cases that you know a
general facilitator can handle along with
anxiety and some other things that we
potentially allow later on in the program.
But PTSD and end of life,
I think for sure can I,
I feel like I want to .
1 more thing out is that as we are
offering this reciprocity to people for
the first year of the program and we're
rolling the program out a year early.
We're letting the first of the market be
the ones that are most resourced to go
out of state for training.
And we're also taking those training
opportunities away from people who are
fully capable of training our own people
here in New Mexico.
So I just want to bring that up.
OK, thank you, Chris.
OK.
I believe next is Greg Evans.
Greetings.
I will address the the reciprocity.
I think it should come with a trigger to
be reassessed and I think it's very
realistic that training infrastructure
for the state of New Mexico could take
multiple years to become established to
the point of the demand.
I wanted to get one point of
clarification on the question about self
administration.
When we're talking about chain of custody
going from the producer,
are you suggesting that the medicine is
to be delivered on the day of
administration and the exchange would
need to be from the patient or to from
the producer to the patient?
Or is there an established chain of
custody plan for provider to pay, pay for,
receive medicine,
hold it and hand the product to the
patient in the setting of administration?
I think that there is.
I've heard mixed interpretations of that
and I feel like it requires some clarity.
Then I have one more when you're done.
Sure.
So just to make sure that I've got it is
to add something as far as a reset
reassessment for the alternative pathway.
And then just to clarify, Greg,
are you suggesting longer than one year
or just making a note that it may take a
couple of years to get educational
programs set up in New Mexico?
Yeah, I mean,
I think longer than one year.
I think realistically it's going to take
longer to get education facilities fully
established,
especially if they're going to be home
grown.
If we have Usona sending in their army to
like build a school or take over an
institution, done.
That's fine.
But like the if the spirit is to have
things home grown,
it could take some time.
And I think we should just kind of like
revisit that and have triggers for
reassessing that.
OK, great.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
And then so then on to the question as
far as the delivery,
some of that still has to be determined,
which is probably why you're hearing
different things from different people.
That's actually a part of the that final
piece.
As far as the final section of that chain
of custody,
once it does reach the the approved
facility or their approved location,
it does need to be determined.
And for example,
we've been working a little bit with
Board of Pharmacy how to ensure for
security.
For the medication during that time.
But the,
I think one of your main questions with
regard to that is would you have to be
the day of delivery?
And the answer is no,
but it shouldn't be something where it's
delivered months in advance.
So there may be some sort of a time frame,
but we're not talking necessarily on day
of delivery.
And there was one of the other committees
where I spoke about how that, you know,
somebody had mentioned that as that's
what should happen and we have talked
about how practically that would be a
problem.
And so, yeah,
but what that time frame exactly is,
we do not know yet.
And again,
that's a part of not even this net,
this set of regulations,
but the next set that we'll be doing,
which will be more specific on the
approved locations.
Cool.
So codifying that that's not codified,
correct.
Thank you so much.
I think that yeah.
Oh,
I was gonna say and then I think you had
another question.
I do, yeah.
I think that we need to include something
that especially when we're talking about
depression,
when we're dealing with contraindications,
when we have somebody with treatment
resistant depression coming into the
program getting going through that gate
of approval,
we need to educate on titration guidance
for contraindicating medications,
which are highly,
highly expected for TDD and possibly PTSD.
The only real medical issues that can
stem from psilocybin are improper
titration and generally land on the SNRI
and SSRI responsibility.
So just wanted to put that in in there
when we're talking about how we're
shaping this education pipeline.
Thank you.
Sure, thank you.
Thank you very much, Greg.
And I think that would fall under some of
the competency areas that we've talked a
little bit about before and and making
those part of the requirements.
So thank you.
I do appreciate it.
And before we jump to the next person on
that's on the list,
there's a question in from Eileen in the
chat just hoping to circle back about end
of life pain care.
And I think we have answered that before,
Eileen,
that that would be a part of the training.
And especially if we do look at it with
some additional endorsements or modules
of talking about how end of life care and
pain care at end of life is going to be
so important.
And that that would be a part of the
training itself.
Not necessarily this particular aspect
and but to make sure and ensure that
that's in there.
Because we've heard that from yourself
and several other people throughout
various committee meetings to ensure that
there is that training with regard to
that,
especially with regard to end of life.
So I hope that helps answers that answer
that.
And then next person that we have in the
list is Catherine Warnock.
Catherine, hi there.
With respect to your question with how
long,
I think until we know what all the
requirements are like,
I think reciprocity could end up being
something we do like long term depending
on what we end up coming up with and if
the other programs are comparable.
I think what I'm more concerned about is
I know some programs out there where you
can get trained and you can have never
guided a single person.
I know some programs that will allow you
to maybe guide one or two people.
I think what we need to really be paying
attention to is experience and hands on
training and coming up maybe with what
are the minimum requirements for
facilitators,
for practitioners and then also for
trainers.
Like I think we need to have a higher
requirement for trainers.
I think if people are training,
they should have significant experience
guiding people.
And I know that that's something that
doesn't exist right now like nationwide.
And I think that's what I think New
Mexico is going to be unique about is
having practicum to help get people the
experience so they can feel confident and,
you know,
have enough experience so that they're
doing this safely so that we're reducing
as much harm as possible.
So that's the first thing.
And then the second thing I wanted to
talk about is what is when are we going
to try to do practicum before the end of
the year so that when we get started,
people are actually ready to start?
Or is that just going to be reciprocity
only and then practicum is happening
later?
I know that in order to have practicum,
we need to have a patience.
So I know that that's also like a,
a sticking point in there.
I'm sure there are some counselors who or
sorry, I shouldn't say counselors,
just any provider who wants to do this
work that could offer themselves as
participants to be dosed if they qualify
under the program with all of, you know,
with the four conditions.
I guess I'm just wondering what that
might look like with respect to timeline.
Are we hoping to try to have some
practical going before the end of the
year or are we going to wait until after
the program's in place?
I also think it's important not only to
have like professional experience,
meaning like hands on dosing,
but there's also the other topic of
personal experience with the medicine,
understanding what the medicine is and
how it works.
So these are just things I wanted to just
bring up.
Yeah, and just have them stated.
Thank you.
Thank you, Catherine.
Actually,
that's a great idea to add in as part of
the requirements that in addition for the
alternative pathway that there needs to
not be just an educational program that's
approved by the other states,
but to have a practicum component of it,
whether with that particular program or
elsewhere.
And to be able to provide proof.
If we were to add something like that,
what sort of length of time or you had
mentioned, you know,
doing at least having worked, you know,
and going through guiding a few different
patients,
what would you think would be a good
measure of that?
Yeah, I mean,
I don't think I should really be the
decider of that, but I would say that,
you know, the more the better, right?
I think it takes a good 10 to before you
start like seeing patterns of I don't
know if 10 is reasonable or not for
people because that's 10 full days, right?
Maybe we make it 5.
Maybe I don't know the answer to that.
I just,
I just feel really uncomfortable having
somebody who's never who's only done it
maybe once or twice going out there and
starting to do this work or even training
others to do this work.
So that's, that's just a concern I have.
Again, I,
I don't think I'm should necessarily be
the decider,
but I'd like to just weigh in on it.
No, and I appreciate, I appreciate that.
Catherine,
I'm not asking for you to be a decider.
Just when we talk about these things,
we always need a bit of a starting point.
What what we tend to notice is otherwise
everyone says, yes, we should have this,
but nobody talks about those details.
And so that's where I'm trying to just
get that.
So this is a good start.
I mean, if I had to pick, I would say 10,
OK.
And we'll have, I would say 10 to start.
Yeah.
OK, great.
Thank you.
And,
and we do have in there Doctor Sutter
also has mentioned that, you know,
10 would be a good place to start as well.
And so thank you.
We'll we'll also be moving that.
That's not the by the way,
that's just there.
Jump, jump in here real quick.
I think probably with the practicum is
have several mock training with
administrating first and then maybe have,
you know,
several actual practice with the the
medicine.
So I think probably, you know,
so the training is not being like just
thrown in there, but getting, you know,
getting used to the steps in in
administering the the medicine,
sitting with sitting with the the the
patient or the client going through it
wrote and then, OK,
do the actual medicine and have work with
with work it that way.
That way it kind of cost could cost and
also actually hone the practice and the
skill that people need.
Great, thank you, Brenda.
I appreciate that.
And so I've included adding that it
should include the simulated patients for
the part of the practice.
OK, great.
And I think our next person is Denali
Wilson.
Hi,
I have a couple of thoughts and I have
one question.
So I'll start with the question,
but can you walk me through again and
sorry if I missed it and the diagnostic
clinician,
the requirement for a controlled
substance number, can you explain that?
Absolutely, Denali.
So the statute does require they be a
licensed provider in New Mexico.
And so part of that process is to have a
New Mexico controlled substance number.
And by us obtaining that rather than
having to go through several other steps
including their DEA license,
that is a easy simple way to actually get
that number to ensure that they are
licensed here in New Mexico.
OK.
And I think my question around the number,
right,
not all not all those who are have
diagnosing authority to diagnose for the
qualifying condition are also prescribers.
My my guess is that only prescribing
clinicians will require a controlled
substance number.
And So what I want to understand is if
this diagnostic clinician requirement is
intended to be limited to people who are
prescribing clinicians or or not.
And if not, how,
how does someone who is not a prescriber
become a diagnostic clinician?
That's a great question, Denali.
And the answer is yes,
it does need to be somebody who also
would otherwise be a prescriber because
even though,
because we are utilizing the medical
model,
even though this is a substance or a
category, sorry, it has been a long day,
everyone,
even though it is a schedule one,
I kept wanting to say substance one,
but since it is a schedule 1 substance,
there can't actually be prescription or
prescriptive authority.
However,
to recommend it and to ensure that this
is something where someone has gone
through those medical clinical, you know,
diagnosis and gone through the exams that
would be necessary,
we do to ensure that it's going to be
someone who does have that medical
licensure.
And so by doing it this way,
that ensures that aspect and that they do
have that authority.
OK.
I, I,
I don't want to spend too much time here,
but I, I,
I'm not sure that I've heard from,
and we have like a lot of conversations
and safety or another subcommittee,
sorry if I'm forgetting which one around
the authority.
And I,
my perception from that was that the,
the consensus,
the community consensus was that,
you know, the, the,
to operate in this space,
A clinician need not be a prescriber,
but does need to have diagnostic
authority.
And I think what we've,
what it looks like is that the department
is,
it is adopting a de facto prescriber
requirements.
I recognize that that's not true for the
practitioner, but I, I think right,
if we are, if the,
the diagnostic clinician is the entry
point into this program, right,
If you have to have a qualifying
condition.
And so I think to limit it to that scope
of clinicians in our, in our state.
I,
I don't agree that it is required by the
statute.
The statute requires that it be someone
who can qualify them and that
qualification is based on diagnosis.
But like right where I attempt therapy
and have for years and years, you know,
there's not a prescriptive clinician in
that practice.
But there's very few in the state that
have medication management,
like therapy practices with medication
management and prescribing clinicians
inside.
So I have a couple of other thoughts
about this,
but would like to hear from others to
about the that particular piece.
I'm wondering on the training programs,
I hear that the department can't limit
the cost and,
and recognize that there isn't
jurisdiction or authority to do that.
I'm,
I'm wondering if there might be a
creative way for us to ensure and protect
people from who might receive, you know,
targeted advertising about training
opportunities who don't actually qualify
for, for participation in the program.
So what I don't want to see is
advertising targeted to people in the
program.
Have people put down deposits in for
training, but they're not licensed.
The healthcare providers,
they don't meet these other
qualifications.
So I'm wondering if the department might
have the ability to require out of state
providers to include as an eligibility
requirement for their program.
If they're working with people in New
Mexico, you know,
do screening for their own individual
screening for eligibility to make sure
that people who wouldn't be eligible to
operate in our program because they're
not licensed healthcare providers,
that they not be.
Yeah,
but they not spend a ton of money on on
training programs and not be eligible.
And then I,
I just wanted to echo Chris in this
bigger question about specialized
conditions that might need individual
training.
I,
I want to agree that that trauma and
complex PTSD, you know,
maybe a place where an individual module
would be helpful,
whether that is stand alone or certainly,
you know, a part of a part of the,
the state specific training.
I think that's, that's a good flag.
And then I, Gregory,
to your mention of treatment resistant
depression,
specifically around training that people
may need around tapering meds or
contraindications, as you mentioned.
And then just in, in general, I think I,
I share the concern that I've heard
already around equity.
I think, you know, I,
I'm sitting here trying to think of like,
OK,
how do we make sure that folks in New
Mexico who haven't already spent
thousands of dollars to go to out of
state trainings that they have that
opportunity?
And I know that that's not within the
scope and role of the Department of
Health as an agency, but I,
I'm curious whether that might be a
philanthropic opportunity for someone in
New Mexico.
You know,
we've had some really great homegrown
philanthropy and providing scholarships
for people to go out of state.
But it's a major concern because if we as,
as Chris and others have said, you know,
if the first,
if the only people who are able to
operate as this program enrolls are those
who have already spent, you know,
an incredible amount of personal
resources to be trained out of state.
You know, that's, that's not,
that's not all New Mexicans.
And I,
I just want to be thinking about what,
what reality that shapes in terms of our,
our, our provider base.
And that's all great.
Thank you, Denali.
I do definitely appreciate it.
And I think one of the things that that I
should mention is part of what we are
trying to do here with the rules and
regulations is not just have the
alternative, that's just one piece on it,
this alternative pathway,
but to really by the end of the summer
have the full requirements with regard to
education and education programs,
you know,
in place or at least well on its way so
that there can be programs starting to be
developed here in New Mexico.
And there already are several, in fact,
several of the people that are on this
call have been working on having
different programs.
And so I do think that we will have some
programs in New Mexico fairly quickly
once those regulations do get out there
as far as getting promulgated and
accepted.
So while I share those concerns,
because the last thing that we want to do
is actually have something where there
are no programs in New Mexico for
training and that people do have to go
out of of state and that's come up
multiple times.
But there also has been that concern that,
well,
what about people who already have gone
through the expense of the training,
have lived here in New Mexico for decades
and would they then have to reinvest and
do additional funds,
an additional expense just to get trained
here.
And So what we're really trying to do is
balance that as best as possible.
And part of that is having this
alternative pathway,
but also trying to get those regulations
out there so that the the more New Mexico
grown, so to speak,
educational programs can get there.
And again,
as mentioned and there's just a comment
in the chat,
we do not yet have those regulations.
That is a part of what we're doing now.
This is all part of that same set of
regulations to get those requirements for
the training programs and to be able to
get them approved and vetted here in New
Mexico.
So this is all part of the same process.
And we're trying to get it so that it
does have that equity,
both the equity for New Mexico programs
to be able to establish and also equity
for people here in New Mexico so that
they don't have to go to additional
expense to get trained and to be able to
practice in New Mexico.
But it's a balancing act.
And so we're hoping that we do this in a
way that will help and,
and have a much more equitable access for
everyone.
And by the way,
thank you also for pointing out Denali
about the fact that there have indeed
been, you know,
quite a few agencies and organizations
and nonprofits that have done
philanthropy and have already been
helping in this regard as far As for
people to get training elsewhere.
So hopefully they'll continue to do that
and.
My hope is, quite frankly,
there be more of them because we do need
that.
We do need to have a very nice,
a very broad provider basis because we
have so many areas in New Mexico that not
just with regard to psychedelics,
but with regard to other medical care
that we need additional coverage.
And hopefully this will be one way to
help provide at least one service in some
of those areas.
Anyway, before I continue to pontificate,
I think the next person is Sky.
Hi there.
Hi.
Hi, Dominic.
First of all, Catherine and Denali,
you guys hit it out of the ballpark with
those questions.
You actually answered a lot of mine in
the conversation.
But one thing I wanted to bring up and
maybe it was already discussed.
Well,
it was talked about people who are
already doing these journeys with years
of experience, who have had, you know,
a lot of people they've brought into
journeys.
And you'll excuse me,
I have a bad back right now.
So I'm trying to focus and I'm in a lot
of pain,
but I really want to get this out.
Could,
could the DoH consider having them be,
you know,
at the top of the chain for the
experience and what they've had over the
years being, you know,
people who have done it instead of people
who have just been trained and gone
through 5 or 10 journeys?
Have have you thought about that?
Is it making sense?
Because before my question was about
applications for those who train.
But you answered it.
So let me, I'm not 100% sure Sky.
Let me see if I'm understanding.
So you want to know about for people who,
who have the experience,
how they could potentially become
practitioners.
Is that really what?
Yeah, for people who are already doing it.
I know a lot of people who are journeying
people on psilocybin and, you know,
they've had years of experience,
a lot of clients.
And if they wanted to obtain a permit
with all the experience they bring forth,
would those people be, you know,
facilitators you'd have at the top of
your list,
whether it's therapist or whomever they
are, you know, healers.
I'm,
I'm trying to be very clear how it sounds
like.
It's kind of stupid right now.
I don't mean to be, but yeah,
I'm just trying to get very clear about
this.
So if it's somebody who has one of the
licenses that we've sort of mentioned
before.
So if they have for example,
behavioral health therapist license,
they would fall into that practitioner
category,
so that therapist category and they would
be able to apply for a permit on that
once they complete the required education.
And, and as we've mentioned,
that education is still to be outlined.
And then similar with regard to the
diagnostic clinician,
if they do not have a license, however,
then they would be able to go through the
training and to become a facilitator.
But regardless of how much experience
someone might have,
they're still going to have to go through
some form of training because we need to
be able to assess.
And,
and part of the purpose of training is
really at the end of any kind of training
is assessment.
And it's to assess.
Do they have that competency?
Do they have those skills,
the skills that are needed?
And so they would still need to go
through that portion of that in order so
that we can ensure that they do indeed
have those skills.
And if it's someone who does have a lot
of experience,
then that should be something that would
not be.
Well,
not to say that it isn't difficult to do
the work and to do that,
but that would be something that they
should be able to then accomplish.
OK, I think you clarified it.
Thank you so much, Dominic.
You're welcome, Sky,
and I hope you feel better.
I hope your back feels better soon.
Thank you.
And then I think next we have Hanifa.
Hi, yes, can you hear me?
Yes, awesome.
I have a couple of points.
1 is that I would say in terms of your
direct ask of in terms of the timing for
the reciprocity slash alternative path,
to me it seems logical that maybe one
year after New Mexico has created its own
in state programming that that
reciprocity or alternative path would be
acceptable.
I think that would give enough time and
also kind of bake that trigger into once
the system here is already set up and
also then give people who might have been
in the middle of training once to Mexico
set up the time to complete their
training, etcetera.
And then, you know,
we've been talking a lot about education
and training when it comes to
practitioners and facilitators.
And I'm very curious about the training
or certificate that's will be needed for
up and coming propagators,
the cultivators, people growing,
people who want to become growers.
So I'm curious like what is that training
and licensing and certification look like?
Is that separate?
Is it baked into a longer training?
And then within that, you know,
unlike Oregon and Colorado,
New Mexico will be using multiple
cultivars or different types of mushrooms,
not just one.
So it seems like to me that in the DoH
specific training that those,
that those medicines and how they work
and the, the,
the psychotic science behind them needs
to be a part of that module.
So it's not.
So it's standardized and not forgotten.
Thank you.
Thank you, Hanifa.
And and I apologize,
I couldn't hear you for parts of it.
There was some background noise.
So if I miss something,
please let me know.
But essentially, yes,
a lot of these are the requirements that
will need to be in the training itself.
And if there are some of the areas and,
and you just brought up one that has been
brought up before and,
and should really be in the New Mexico
portion of the module,
it would be about potential different
species or different cultivars of
psychedelic mushrooms.
And to ensure that there is that
knowledge and understanding and there's
going to be other areas that will include
that.
This is really just the start.
And as I mentioned in the next meeting,
that's when we're really going to talk
about some of the competencies.
But some of the additional aspects that
needs to go in there will be what exactly
will need to go into that New Mexico
module that may, you know, be, you know,
that may be available in some of the
trainings elsewhere,
but not in all of them.
And So what do we need to ensure is going
to be in that?
And part of what we're also doing for
that is we're looking at some of these
other curricula to really sort of decide
and, and figure out, OK,
what is really being taught and trained
in these other places.
And we don't have an answer on that
because I think currently there's about
24 different trainings between Colorado
and Oregon.
And so looking, looking at that aspect.
So I hope that captures what you were
trying to say.
00 And then the point about the one year.
Thank you for the answer on that portion.
But if there's something that I missed,
please, if you can say, yeah, I'm sorry,
thank you.
I'm just out of public place.
The other thing was around what are we,
what,
what are we thinking about in terms of
the training for for propagators and
cultivators?
Oh,
as far as what kind of training
cultivators need to go through,
there's not a specific training on that
with regard to how to cultivate and how
to do that.
But there are quite a few programs here
in New Mexico already that do teach
people about mycology and growing.
And, and in fact,
many of those individuals have been on,
on the various calls,
but that is something that has been
brought up as far as is that something
that could be added down the road.
And the answer on that is yes.
So thank you.
Thank you.
OK.
And I think next we have Chris Caldwell.
Yeah, Thank you.
Hi again.
I wanted to comment on what I had read in
the chat because maybe I'm
misunderstanding it,
but Deb Thorne and and Ruben Sutter were
talking about the need for Hospice
professionals to help support training or
to support training our courses.
The majority of our instructors are
either Hospice chaplains,
Hospice or palliative care physicians,
or they have Hospice training in in other
professional roles.
So that's something that's really
important to us.
And I also wanted to say there's no extra
cost.
I'm not sure I understood Deb's point.
And we are a non profit and we do offer
scholarships.
Thank you, Chris.
I think the concern there as far as the
cost is for many of these other programs,
there are costs for depending on credit
hours, that sort of thing.
And so knowing that there is a nonprofit
with no cost for that particular type of
training is great.
So thank you.
And then just because of being cognizant
of time,
we only have about 9 minutes left.
So Larry does have his hand up.
So I'd like to go to Larry.
And then at this point,
we've gotten a lot of feedback and I
really appreciate it.
And what I'll do is after Larry has
spoken,
I'm going to turn it back on over to
Brenda for our closing.
And then remember this is,
this is to hear feedback and get it.
We'll work on incorporating and be
bringing it back to the next meeting as
far as with some of the potential changes
and some of the ideas that have been
brought and and also next time looking at
competencies and that part is for the
training and education.
So I'll let Larry go ahead and talk and
then I'm going to be quiet unless Larry
has a question for me.
Thank you.
Dom.
I,
I just want to mention about re
administration.
I put something in the chat for at least
two of the conditions.
It's, I think it's going to be essential,
I think for end of life.
A lot of people the, the,
the wisdom is to start kind of low and
then to increase them.
And so it, it adds some complexity.
In other words,
we have to have some way that if a
certain amount of psilocybin is dropped
off, there's a way to return it back or,
or such.
And I think also in that situation,
probably the administration does need the
help of the, you know,
of the practitioner to to be guiding
there.
I think the other one that's going to
come up is depression.
As we have people that are on
antidepressants,
they often don't respond to the initial
dose and need more.
So I think early on we should look for a
way to deal with that complexity,
which I imagine is going to require some
path to returning the psilocybin to once
it came if it's not used.
Thank you, good points.
OK, and thank you everybody.
Really do appreciate the feedback and the
conversation.
Again,
this is the starting point and you know
some really great things to add on in
including some of the the ideas as far as
practicums and the potential for other
endorsements for lack of a better word at
the moment for some of the other
conditions and really kind of moving
forward and there were many others.
But we are only have a few minutes left.
So I want to turn it over to Brenda for
any additional items or last minute.
And I think Brenda,
we do have to determine next meeting time.
OK, Well, thank you, Dominic.
Thank you everyone for this was a great
meeting.
I mean,
your participation is vital in
constructing what we need to do here in
New Mexico.
So I think that we are we're we're
actually getting closer and closer.
Things are getting tighter and tighter.
And I like seeing this because before
when we all started, it was kind of like,
well, what are we doing?
What are what's happening here?
You know, how much is this?
Where's it going to where's trading going
to be?
Where's it?
So that's still all formed emulating,
but as we are going along,
we're not reinventing the wheel.
We're just making it more for New Mexico
and that's where we need to focus.
And I think going back to the question of
like, OK,
how are we going to do it home grown?
Well, we are,
we are adapting all of the knowledge that
we have and we're,
we're setting up ways to be trained and
educated on this.
And I think we're,
we're getting closer and closer actually
we're moving very quickly,
but we're also being very safe about it
too,
which I really love because this is where
the rubber really meets the road.
We really have to meet the the patients
and the clients where they are and go
from there because this is not just a
cookie cutter type of thing.
This is a very intricate,
intricate work and very personal for our
patients.
So I'm really happy that we have such a
beautiful community of people that are
coming together and offering up all of
this knowledge,
all of these questions that need to be
answered.
And I want to thank you all for coming
here today.
This was one of I, I, I think a very,
very engaging meeting today and I hope to
see you at the next one.
So what do we have Dominic Free on the
calendar?
So the question would be as far as
frequency,
next Friday is the board meeting.
So I would suggest if we follow the every
two weeks,
that would be Friday the 22nd and that
time frame is open at this time from 1:00
to 3:00.
Perfect.
That would that would work.
And then Larry is putting in the comment
for end of life to do June, I'm sorry,
June 5th from 1:00 to 3:00 with that.
Is there any objection to that for
individuals?
It does look like that is open on the
Department of Health side as well.
OK,
so it sounds like we have both meetings
set.
So for that we have the 22nd for the next
training and education and June 5th for
the next end of life.
OK, well, thank you everybody.
And Brenda or Larry,
any last minute words?
No, thank you for coming here today.
This was this was really nice.
Thank you everybody.
Have a great Friday and happy Mother's
Day.
So I stole that one from you this time,
Jorge.
Thanks everybody.
Hope we can do more joint meetings.
I think they're really helpful.